I am Full Stack developer and AWS Certified Solution Architect. My Career is spanning more than **10 years**. My Passion is to write Clean, Elegant & Scalable Code. I Love to follow latest trends and best practices in software engineering. I am Strong believer that success lies in balancing the fine line between "YAGNI" and "Do IT Right First Time" Coding philosophies. Creating Good Software is continually evolving process and not one time activity.

Niraj Sonawane

Contact No: 9022179599, Email: Niraj.Sonawane@Gmail.Com

Blog: https://nirajsonawane.github.io/



Most Proud Of

Limit Monitoring System Migration Journey

- Migrated Monolithic Backend Services to Microservices architecture
- Moved the new and old Services to Bank's Cloud Platform. Reduce the cost associated with managing the physical hardware.
- Created Reusable JWT Authentication library, Which is now used by Multiple teams
- Centralized the cross cutting concerns of Microservices using Spring Cloud Gateway.
- Moved the Database dominated business processing to java services.

Aggregation Data Services

- Created Highly Scalable Batch Application For sourcing trade Stress Data for 5 Million Trades. Framework is capable of Collecting, sorting and Distributing Error information about the run and stress calculations to relevant stakeholders. Reduced the operational tasks by 40%
- Created Framework to automate the database regression for ADS component of Risk Reporting Framework.
- Created Webapp for manual data upload to provide capability to business owners to override data. Reduced the IT Dependency by 100%

Event Based Notification Component

- Migrated scattered notification processing components to event based architecture, There by reducing the tight coupling between multiple system componets by 100%.
- ➤ Centralized The Notification Processing Business process.

Experience

- Working As Senior Software Engg in Finleanp Germany [November 2019 to Till Date]
- Working As Assistant Vice President in Deutsche Bank [August 2015 to November 2019]

Education

Bachelor of engineering - IT

Pune University, 2008

Higher School Certificate H.S.C

Maharashtra State Board 2004

Secondary School Certificate H.S.C

Maharashtra State Board 2002

Technical Skills

Java: Core Java, J2EE, Java 8, 9 & 10, Junit

Spring: Spring Core, JDBC, JMS, AOP, MVC Batch, REST, Test, Boot, WebFlux and Reactor

Spring Cloud: Cloud Config, Cloud Gateway Eureka Naming Server, Hystrix, Feign.

Streaming Technologies: Apache ActiveMQ, Reactive Streams RXJava 2

DevOps, Cloud Technologies:

Docker, Kubernetes and OpenShift

Automation Testing: Cucumber, Fitnesse,

Selenium & DBFit

Database: Oracle & MySql.

UI Technologies: Struts 2, Angular5 **Tools and Servers:** Team City, Jenkins, Apache Tomcat, Sonar, Control-M, Git, SVN

Others: Kotlin, Android

- ➤ Worked As **Tech Lead** in **Barclays** [Aug 2012-August 2015]
- ➤ Worked As **Software Developer in BNP Paribas** [June-2011 August 2012]
- Worked As Junior Developer in Cappemini [Nov-2008 June 11]

Technical Certifications

- > AWS Certified Solution Architect Associate.
- Sun Certified Java Programmer for JDK 1.5. (SCJP)
- Sun Certified Web Component Developer Enterprise Edition 5 (SCWCD)
- > IBM SOA Fundamentals

Awards and Recognitions

- > Spot award in Deutsche Bank Q2-2017
- > Spot award in Deutsche Bank Q1-2016
- Outstanding Contribution Award in Barclays 2015
- Project Star Award in Capgemini 2009

Contact

- ➤ Mobile 91 -9022179599
- Email Niraj.Sonawane@gmail.com
- **▶** Blog
- **➢** Github
- > Portfolio
- StackOverflow
- > Linkedin

Professional Skills

Solution Design & Prototypes Software Automation Agile Development Clean Code & Refactoring.

Personal Skills

Problem-solving Abilities
Analytical
Leadership and Mentoring
Adaptable
Motivated
Team player

Domains

Banking and Financial Services. Aviation